let savollar9 = [
    {
      numb: 1,
      question: "to ail",
      answer: "C. azob bermoq",
      options: [
        "A. davolamoq",
        "B. parvarish qilmoq",
        "C. azob bermoq",
        "D. tuzatmoq"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 2,
      question: "ally",
      answer: "B. ittifoqchi",
      options: [
        "A. dushman",
        "B. ittifoqchi",
        "C. hamkasb",
        "D. qo'shni"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 3,
      question: "to boast",
      answer: "A. maqtanmoq",
      options: [
        "A. maqtanmoq",
        "B. gaplashmoq",
        "C. shivirlamoq",
        "D. muhokama qilmoq"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 4,
      question: "to bounce",
      answer: "D. sakramoq",
      options: [
        "A. tushmoq",
        "B. otmoq",
        "C. dumalatmoq",
        "D. sakramoq"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 5,
      question: "bully",
      answer: "C. bezori",
      options: [
        "A. do'st",
        "B. o'quvchi",
        "C. bezori",
        "D. o'qituvchi"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 6,
      question: "carbohydrate",
      answer: "B. uglevod",
      options: [
        "A. oqsil",
        "B. uglevod",
        "C. vitamin",
        "D. mineral"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 7,
      question: "to crawl",
      answer: "A. emaklamoq",
      options: [
        "A. emaklamoq",
        "B. yugurmoq",
        "C. sakramoq",
        "D. yurmoq"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 8,
      question: "to defeat",
      answer: "C. yengmoq",
      options: [
        "A. kurashmoq",
        "B. yutqazmoq",
        "C. yengmoq",
        "D. taslim bo'lmoq"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 9,
      question: "dial",
      answer: "B. siferblat",
      options: [
        "A. strelka",
        "B. siferblat",
        "C. batareya",
        "D. mexanizm"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 10,
      question: "dominant",
      answer: "D. hukmron",
      options: [
        "A. kuchsiz",
        "B. oddiy",
        "C. tinch",
        "D. hukmron"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 11,
      question: "mercy",
      answer: "A. rahm",
      options: [
        "A. rahm",
        "B. jazo",
        "C. qasos",
        "D. ayb"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 12,
      question: "to nod",
      answer: "C. bosh qimirlatmoq",
      options: [
        "A. bosh chayqamoq",
        "B. bosh egmoq",
        "C. bosh qimirlatmoq",
        "D. bosh burmoq"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 13,
      question: "opponent",
      answer: "B. raqib",
      options: [
        "A. hamkor",
        "B. raqib",
        "C. do'st",
        "D. hamkasb"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 14,
      question: "to quarrel",
      answer: "D. janjallashmoq",
      options: [
        "A. o'ynamoq",
        "B. gaplashmoq",
        "C. kulmoq",
        "D. janjallashmoq"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 15,
      question: "rival",
      answer: "A. raqobatchi",
      options: [
        "A. raqobatchi",
        "B. yordamchi",
        "C. do'st",
        "D. maslahatchi"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 16,
      question: "sore",
      answer: "C. og'riqli",
      options: [
        "A. sog'lom",
        "B. kuchli",
        "C. og'riqli",
        "D. charchagan"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 17,
      question: "to sting",
      answer: "B. sanchmoq",
      options: [
        "A. tirnamoq",
        "B. sanchmoq",
        "C. urmoq",
        "D. tishlamoq"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 18,
      question: "to strain",
      answer: "D. zo'r bermoq",
      options: [
        "A. dam olmoq",
        "B. bo'shashmoq",
        "C. taslim bo'lmoq",
        "D. zo'r bermoq"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 19,
      question: "torture",
      answer: "C. azob",
      options: [
        "A. o'yin",
        "B. mashq",
        "C. azob",
        "D. mehnat"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 20,
      question: "to wrestle",
      answer: "A. kurashmoq",
      options: [
        "A. kurashmoq",
        "B. boks tushmoq",
        "C. raqsga tushmoq",
        "D. yugurmoq"
      ]
    }
];

export default savollar9;